Warn sales people about products soon to
be out of stock.
People who enter sales documents in
Business Central should always be able
to enter new orders and invoices and not
necessarily have to worry about
inventory levels.
Because an inventory level is time
sensitive,
you may replenish your inventory before
you actually need to ship products to
customers.
No one should be blocked with entering
sales documents.
However,
you may want to inform people entering
these sales documents that the entry
they're making will pull the inventory
into negative state once the sales
document is posted.
And by default,
Business Central will display a message
that it warns users about the would-be
negative inventory level when
registering the sales line where if the
order was posted right now, there
wouldn't be available inventory at the
chosen location.
Let's see how that works.
Let's go to a sales order.
I go to sales in the top navigation
menu,
sales orders, and pick one from the
list.
I go to the sales lines.
Let's say I wanted to sell 50 of this
Atlanta whiteboard.
We now see that Business Central shows
me a message that there isn't enough
inventory available at this location.
This won't mean anything right now when
I'm registering this sales order line,
but it will when the order is posted.
Notice though that the quantity I enter
here, even if the order is not posted
yet, it will have an effect on the
demand of this product.
If I don't want to see these messages
when I enter sales lines for some
reason, I can disable it.
This is done at the sales and
receivables setup page.
So, at the tell me search, I bring up
with the LQ, I can enter
sales and receivables,
and you'll find the sales and
receivables setup on the list.
I select it.
I want to find the field called stock
out warning.
This is the field that determines
whether or not I see that warning when I
try to enter and quantity on a sales
line.
In this case, let's disable it.
Let's go back to the sales order.
And we select the first one on the list.
Now, we enter a new quantity. Let's say
100.
Now, I won't be bothered with any
information about this inventory level
on this product being pulled into
negative state.
And that way, you can determine if you
want to warn your sales people about
products soon to be out of stock.
Thank you for watching.